# JOSEPH HANSEN









I am a strategic communicator with passions for problem solving, visual design, and coding.

I've worked as a WordPress developer, an assistant manager for a multi-county community advocacy organization and more. I learn quickly, adapt rapidly, and fit into a team instantaneously.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Lemonade Stand

2021-2023

Wordpress Developer

- Create sites (WordPress) from scratch to client specifications
- Build custom solutions to client requests using PHP and JavaScript
- Address and solve client tickets (130+ yearly)
- Maintain site security and health for clients

#### Frozen Dessert Supplies

2019-2021

Marketing Specialist

- Managed Amazon and Walmart advertising
- Managed email marketing

# Faculty Technology Center (BYU-I) Faculty Assistant/Motion Graphics Artist

2019 - 2021

- Answered difficult technology questions from faculty, cheerfully and effectively (phone, office visits, and emails)
- Transitioned an entire campus to remote learning using innovative solutions
- Worked with a team to find, troubleshoot, and develop solutions to complex issues with learning management system
- Created multimedia materials for faculty, including web development and animation

#### VOICE Advocacy

2016 - 2019

Project Manager/Assistant Manager

- Worked closely with director to perfect and execute her vision
- Increased projects by 260% and expanded influence across 13 counties
- Built and maintained website (WordPress), through several iterations
- Gained experience in critical thinking, leadership, professional communication, and rapid response due to complex organizational challenges
- Supervised graphic design and created several published reports

#### Equilibrium Natural Health

2019

Social/Web/Email Marketing Manager

- Managed marketing on Facebook, ActiveCampaign, Instagram, and Google
- Built and maintained website (WordPress)
- Wrote and edited blogs/emails/other promotional content

#### **Building Hope Today**

2017-2018

Creative Consultant/Graphic Designer (internship)

• Created professional presentations, booklets, and other graphical material

#### Soapbox Agency Graphic Designer

2018

- Learned to get a job done in high-stress situations efficiently, gaining experience in taking initiative and learning on the go
- Worked with difficult clients and learned to interpret unclear directives

### **EDUCATION**

Brigham Young University-Idaho Bachelor's of Strategic Communication - Apr. 2021

## SKILLS

- WordPress (5+ years), Squarespace, Shopify, Webflow
- JavaScript, Node.js, Express, React, Redux
- WooCommerce
- WordPress builders- Flatsome, Elementor, Divi, WP Bakery, Avada, etc
- Excel/Google Sheets, Google Scripts, Zapier, N8N
- Python (6+ years), Django, PyQtGui, Tkinter, BlenderPython
- Heroku, Digital Ocean, Ghost.org, GitHub, Cloudflare
- PHP, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, C++
- CSS, Bootstrap, Bulma, Tailwind
- Google Ads/Facebook Ads/Pinterest Ads
- ActiveCampaign/Email Marketing/Email Campaigns + List Management
- Video Editing/Animation, Blender
- Graphic Design- Adobe (6+ years), Affinity, Krita, Inkscape, GIMP

# VOLUNTEERING

- Crisis Counselor for The Trevor Project's TrevorChat program
- Community Moderator for BlenderArtists.org

### **AWARDS**

Gordon B. Hinckley Outstanding Communication Graduate

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures (FreeCodeCamp)
- MERN From Scratch (Udemy)
- OPR Institute Certified Suicide Prevention Trainer